<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on harmonyhealthclinic</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on harmonyhealthclinic</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Acupuncture Consultation and Personalized Care</title><link>/services/acupuncture-consultation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/services/acupuncture-consultation/</guid><description>Start with a brief virtual consultation, then mobile acupuncture visits with clear follow-up planning and fair pricing.</description></item><item><title>What Is Acupuncture?</title><link>/blog/what-is-acupuncture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/what-is-acupuncture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is one of the primary treatments under the Traditional Chinese Medicine umbrella, and it has a longer history than herbs. Its first written mention was around 100 BCE, and many scholars believe it was used several centuries earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Chinese medicine, health depends on the balance of yin and yang, qi (chee) and blood, and the functional harmony of organs and meridians. Imbalance is considered the root of disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dr. Dan Wang</title><link>/team/dr-dan-wang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate><guid>/team/dr-dan-wang/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Originally from Northeast China, Dan brings a rich cultural and clinical background rooted in Traditional Chinese Medicine. She earned her degree from the Liaoning University of Traditional Chinese Medicine in the 1990s and has been practicing in the western suburbs of Chicago for the past four years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan is deeply passionate about Chinese medical philosophy and integrates practices such as Taiji, Yijing, and Feng Shui into her holistic approach. She believes true healing comes from achieving balance, both mentally and physically, and she works closely with each patient to support that harmony.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Acute and Chronic Pain Management</title><link>/services/pain-and-injury-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/services/pain-and-injury-management/</guid><description>Acupuncture care for musculoskeletal pain, headaches, nerve-related symptoms, and injury recovery.</description></item><item><title>Does Acupuncture Hurt?</title><link>/blog/does-acupuncture-hurt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/does-acupuncture-hurt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture needles are hair-thin filiform needles. They are different from the hollow syringes used for injections or blood draws, and insertion is virtually painless for most people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Points on the hands, feet, and face can occasionally be more sensitive, but this is usually brief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During treatment, some people feel sensations such as soreness, numbness, bloating, heaviness, warmth, coolness, or even brief itching. These sensations are often temporary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After needling, most people feel a deep sense of calm and relaxation. This is often when people notice the treatment beginning to work, and when acupuncture starts to heal.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Much Does Mobile Acupuncture Cost?</title><link>/blog/how-much-does-mobile-acupuncture-cost/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-much-does-mobile-acupuncture-cost/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Our mobile services currently have a base commute rate of $29.99 for each commute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before booking further appointments, patients complete a brief virtual consultation for $20.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We keep acupuncture rates fair and provide package options and senior discounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For package and senior discount information, call 630-408-7875.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Women's Health and Fertility Support</title><link>/services/womens-health-and-fertility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/services/womens-health-and-fertility/</guid><description>Holistic acupuncture care for cycle health, fertility, hormonal transitions, and pelvic wellness.</description></item><item><title>Digestive and Metabolic Health</title><link>/services/digestive-and-metabolic-health/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/services/digestive-and-metabolic-health/</guid><description>Support for abdominal discomfort, IBS, and metabolic health concerns including cholesterol, weight, and blood sugar balance.</description></item><item><title>How Many Sessions Will I Need?</title><link>/blog/how-many-sessions-will-i-need/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-many-sessions-will-i-need/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The number of sessions depends on your condition and how long you have had it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, the more chronic the issue, the longer the treatment course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture works by restoring balance and supporting your body&amp;rsquo;s natural healing mechanisms, so it can take time to see clear results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical recommendation is about twice per week for severe pain, or weekly treatment for four to six weeks for many other concerns before judging whether acupuncture is helping.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Respiratory, Immune, and Skin Support</title><link>/services/respiratory-immune-and-skin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/services/respiratory-immune-and-skin/</guid><description>Acupuncture for allergy, asthma, sinus, cough, skin, and facial nerve concerns.</description></item><item><title>What Can Acupuncture Treat?</title><link>/blog/what-can-acupuncture-treat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/what-can-acupuncture-treat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The most common concerns patients visit us for include pain, anxiety, sinus congestion, insomnia, energy improvement, ear problems, digestion issues, fertility, IVF support, postpartum care, and menopause support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture can help reduce pain after injury, but it is wise to see a medical doctor first to rule out fractures and structural damage before beginning acupuncture treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Stress, Sleep, and Preventive Wellness</title><link>/services/stress-sleep-and-wellness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/services/stress-sleep-and-wellness/</guid><description>Whole-person acupuncture care for anxiety, fatigue, insomnia, addiction support, and healthy aging.</description></item><item><title>What Are the Risks of Acupuncture?</title><link>/blog/what-are-the-risks-of-acupuncture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/what-are-the-risks-of-acupuncture/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Licensed acupuncturists receive thorough training in needling techniques and safety, so the risk of serious side effects is very small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common side effects are minor bleeding, mild bruising at the needle site, or occasional dizziness after treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special caution is needed for people taking blood thinner medication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electro-acupuncture may not be suitable for people with pacemakers. Acupuncture without electric stimulation is good enough to help those patients.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What Is Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM)?</title><link>/blog/what-is-traditional-chinese-medicine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>/blog/what-is-traditional-chinese-medicine/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) has a history of thousands of years. It is a summary of long-term experience in fighting disease and an integral part of traditional Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TCM studies human physiology and pathology, along with diagnosis, prevention, and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its theoretical system is influenced by Yin-Yang and Five Elements theory, guided by a holistic concept, based on internal organs and meridians, and characterized by syndrome differentiation and treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This page has moved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please visit &lt;a href="/team/"&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; for clinic and practitioner information.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We welcome new and returning patients. Call or email us to book your first appointment, ask about treatment plans, or discuss whether acupuncture is a good fit for your health goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="appointment-options"&gt;Appointment options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile service base commute rate: $29.99 per commute&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brief virtual consultation before further booking: $20&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We provide package options and senior discounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For package and senior discount information, call 630-408-7875.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="service-area-zip-codes"&gt;Service area ZIP codes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60001&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60002&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60003&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60004&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60005&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60006&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60007&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60008&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60009&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60010&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
 &lt;thead&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;th&gt;Day&lt;/th&gt;
 &lt;th&gt;Opening Hours&lt;/th&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/thead&gt;
 &lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Monday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;9:00am - 6:00pm&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Tuesday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;9:00am - 6:00pm&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Wednesday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;9:00am - 6:00pm&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Thursday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;9:00am - 6:00pm&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Friday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;9:00am - 5:00pm&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Saturday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;9:00am - 2:00pm&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Sunday&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td&gt;Closed&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>