<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Harmony Acupuncture Clinic</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Harmony Acupuncture Clinic</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Acupuncture?</title>
      <link>/blog/what-is-acupuncture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/what-is-acupuncture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acupuncture is a treatment method from Traditional Chinese Medicine that uses very thin, sterile needles placed at specific points on the body. The goal is to support the body&amp;rsquo;s natural healing response and restore balance across different systems.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many people first try acupuncture for pain, but it is also commonly used for stress, sleep issues, digestive symptoms, and women&amp;rsquo;s health concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-happens-in-a-standard-session&#34;&gt;What happens in a standard session?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brief check-in on current symptoms&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Focused assessment based on your treatment goals&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Needle placement at points selected for your condition&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rest period, usually 20-30 minutes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Follow-up recommendations before your next visit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-treatment-feel-like&#34;&gt;What does treatment feel like?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most patients feel minimal discomfort when needles are inserted. During treatment, people often report a deep sense of relaxation, warmth, or heaviness in the treated area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Acupuncture Supports Pain Recovery</title>
      <link>/blog/acupuncture-for-pain-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/acupuncture-for-pain-recovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pain can come from overuse, injury, poor sleep, stress, or long-standing inflammation. Acupuncture supports recovery by improving local circulation, reducing muscle tension, and helping regulate pain signaling.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is commonly used for neck and back pain, sciatica, headaches, TMJ, tendon irritation, and pain after work, sports, or motor vehicle injuries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;common-pain-conditions-treated&#34;&gt;Common pain conditions treated&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Neck and back pain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sciatica&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Headaches and migraines&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Joint pain in shoulders, knees, and feet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tendon irritation such as tennis elbow and plantar fasciitis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-long-does-it-take-to-feel-improvement&#34;&gt;How long does it take to feel improvement?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some patients feel relief quickly, especially with recent injuries. Chronic conditions often improve gradually over several weeks with consistent treatment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What to Expect at Your First Acupuncture Visit</title>
      <link>/blog/your-first-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/your-first-visit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your first visit is focused on understanding the full picture of your health, not just one symptom. Expect a detailed conversation about your current concerns, medical history, sleep, digestion, stress, and lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;typical-first-visit-flow&#34;&gt;Typical first-visit flow&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intake and health history review&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TCM assessment, including pulse and tongue evaluation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acupuncture treatment during the same visit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Home-care recommendations for the days after treatment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most initial visits are about 90 minutes. Follow-up sessions are usually around 60 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fertility-Focused Supplement Guidance</title>
      <link>/blog/fertility-focused-supplement-guidance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/fertility-focused-supplement-guidance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to conceive, it is easy to feel overwhelmed by supplement advice online. Many plans are complicated, expensive, and not tailored to your needs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our approach is simpler: prioritize real food, consistent routines, and targeted supplementation only when clinically appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-supplement-philosophy&#34;&gt;Our supplement philosophy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use evidence-informed recommendations, not social media trends&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Personalize based on cycle history, labs, and overall health profile&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Avoid &amp;ldquo;kitchen sink&amp;rdquo; stacks that add cost without clear benefit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reassess over time instead of locking into a fixed long list&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;important-safety-reminder&#34;&gt;Important safety reminder&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Always consult your physician or a registered dietitian before adding new supplements, especially if you are using fertility medications, preparing for IVF, or currently pregnant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fertility Acupuncture FAQ</title>
      <link>/blog/fertility-acupuncture-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 09:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/fertility-acupuncture-faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-acupuncture-a-cure-for-infertility&#34;&gt;Is acupuncture a cure for infertility?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No. Acupuncture is not a cure for infertility, but it can be an effective part of a broader fertility care plan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-can-acupuncture-support-fertility&#34;&gt;How can acupuncture support fertility?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Depending on your case, acupuncture may help regulate menstrual cycles, improve blood flow to reproductive organs, reduce stress, and support hormone balance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-acupuncture-be-used-with-iui-or-ivf&#34;&gt;Can acupuncture be used with IUI or IVF?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes. Many patients use acupuncture alongside assisted reproductive care. Timing and frequency are personalized based on your treatment calendar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
